# Aimee Knight

Full-Stack Software Engineer
752 Fox Ridge Drive
Brentwood, TN 37027
(205) 913-4533
AimeeMarieKnight@gmail.com
AimeeMarieKnight.com

I've been writing JavaScript professionally for close to five years on both the front and back end, and am heavily involved in the JavaScript ecosystem. While I'm incredibly passionate and excited about what I do with my "Jr. Dev For Life" mentality, I'm also the kind of developer who believes 100% test coverage is really a bare minimum, and that you should "move fast AND fix things"! Additionally, I'm a Google Developer Expert in Web Technologies, a weekly panelist on the JavaScript Jabber podcast, an international keynote speaker, and mentor for various coding boot camps.

For a list of my conference talks, blog posts, and podcast interviews, please visit <u>GitHub</u> and <u>AimeeMarieKnight.com</u>.

# **Current Summary**

# Built Technologies (Nashville, TN)

#### Full-Stack Software Engineer/2018-Present

As a Software Engineer at Built Technologies, I've worked in a rapidly paced startup environment in the fintech space building out features in React, Can, Node, and PHP. While there, I have been especially focused on rearchitecting legacy portions of our application, and improving the quality of our deliverables by laying the groundwork needed to implement both end to end and unit testing.

#### Strengths include:

- Test-driven development
- Designing/Writing Front End UI's with Angular.js and React
- Designing/Writing APIs with Node
- Staying up to date with the latest technologies and libraries
- Mentoring
- CSS

# JavaScript Jabber & Angular Air

#### Panelist, 2015-Present

 Interview community leaders about various open source projects, and other popular JavaScript and Angular topics.

# Experience

#### Warner Bros Digital Labs (NYC, NY/Remote)

#### Front End Software Engineer/Channel Lead, 2016-2018

- Built out various properties for Warner Bros. including <u>Boomerang</u>, <u>DC Universe</u>, <u>Warner Archive</u>, <u>Moodica</u>, and <u>DramaFever</u> using Angular.js and Django.
- Prepared the code base for the latest version of Angular by migrating to a component model.
- Drove adoption of the latest version of JavaScript by leading weekly internal training.

### Kuali (Lehi, UT/Remote)

#### Full-Stack Software Engineer, 2016

- Built out features for a higher education curriculum management system using React, Redux, and Node with Express and Koa.
- Increasing product reliability and stability by helping to drive adoption of front end test with Enzyme and increasing back end test coverage.
- Helped implement the latest technologies within the code base including WebPack, Flow, JavaScript 2015 and JavaScript 2016.

# Message Systems (Columbia, MD)

#### Full-Stack Software Engineer, 2014-2016

- Built out features for the core on-premise solution, and cloud offering, <u>SparkPost</u> utilizing Angular.js and Node.
- Led migration to ES6 and the official AngularJS style guide.
- Prepared UI for Angular 2.
- Maintained 100% front end and back end test coverage.

#### Nashville Software School (Nashville, TN)

Apprentice - Advanced Alpha Group, 2014-2015

Completed a six-month intensive, full-time, hands-on, fast-moving and rigorous study of software engineering. Emphasis was placed on building database driven applications, and working with other students while immersed in new and challenging material.

Highlights include: - Computer Science fundamentals, algorithms, operating systems and security - Test-driven development with Rspec & Mocha - Ruby \* Ruby on Rails with SQLite and PostgreSQL - JavaScript & Node with MongoDB - Agile software development & pair-programming

# Boost by Design LLC. (Richmond Hill, GA)

#### Junior Web Developer, 2013-2014

- Implement theme modifications for cross-browser support from completed Photoshop design files while maintaining W3C compliance.
- Utilize a mobile first design approach, implementing media queries for all standard breakpoints.
- Address issues with broken themes as well as hosting account configuration.
- Educate clients on Wordpress CMS, SEO, and accessibility best practices.
- Work within tight deadlines to satisfy urgent client requests.

#### Fast Forward Video Inc. (Irvine, CA)

#### Sales and Marketing Administrator, 2012

Manage global customer base and serve as primary CRM administrator.

# Restore Therapy Services Ltd. & Comfort Care Home Health and Hospice LLC. (Birmingham, AL)

#### **Business Development Coordinator, 2009-2010**

- Responsible for overseeing production Web Sites, SEO, and additional marketing material.
- Work with prospects, CEO and Director of Business Development to implement new contracts.

# FitzMartin Inc. (Birmingham, AL)

#### Project Manager/Junior Account Manager, 2007-2009

- Collaborate with Software Developers, Creatives, and Account Executives to ensure projects deadlines are met on time and on budget.
- Set up production schedules for all projects in order to maintain critical path management for an average of 110 jobs per week.

# City of Pelham - Pelham Civic Complex (Pelham, AL)

Private Figure Skating Coach, 2000-2007

Instruct all ages and all levels in various disciplines of Figure Skating.

# **Education**

- Nashville Software School Student / Apprentice Advanced Alpha Group, 2014-2015
- University of Massachusetts at Lowell Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (Continuing Education), 2012-2013
- University of Alabama at Birmingham Summa Cum Laude Bachelor of Arts in Communication Management & Mass Communications, 2002-2007

# **Skills**

- HTML5, Jade & Haml
- · CSS3, Less & Sass
- JavaScript (Including ES6) & jQuery
- Angular.js, React & Redux
- Node
- Ruby/Rails with Rspec
- Django
- Express & Koa
- Mocha, Jasmine & Jest
- Protractor & Selenium
- SQLite, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RethinkDB, ElasticSearch
- Grunt & Gulp
- Vim
- Git
- Amazon Web Services
- TravisCI, Coveralls, & Gemnasium
- Wordpress Theme Development
- Adobe Photoshop and InDesign

# References

References are available upon request.